#### PRADANA PUTRA R.

http://www.pradanapr.com | +62 81 669 1122 or +62 813 60000 954 | pradanapr@pradanapr.com

#### SUMMARY

E-commerce and digital marketing professional with over 8 years of experience, very well versed in brand and product development, strategic business decision making, multichannel digital marketing, strong analytical research skill, deep understanding of content production.

#### **EXPERIENCES**

#### **HEAD OF E-COMMERCE & MEDIA**

2015 - now

NADEKO.co.id, KawaiiBeautyJapan.com, PT. Media Makmur, previously a subsidiary of Rich Media Japan

- · Own the strategy and management of the brand sites, marketplaces, and all digital revenue streams
- Drive team and partners (merchandising, production, and marketing) to create excellence in company's online business
- · Develop strategy, pilot and execution of company's digital marketing
- Growth hack the portal media as well as the e-commerce business
- Create seamless business integration between portal media and e-commerce platform
- Manage online analytics, leveraging e-commerce analyst to execute, developing a leadership position with regards to e-commerce business through data
- Provide regular reporting across the organization, continually improve on reports as the business matures, run ad hoc investigations to answer important questions
- Play a constant role in CRM discussions and rollout
- Lead IT team to manage day-today e-commerce and portal media platform technical operations including site functionality, external testing, etc.

## **INERNATIONAL GROUP DIGITAL & AFFILIATE MARKETING MANAGER**

2013 - 2015

Swiss-Belhotel International Hotels & Resorts

- Handle and lead digital penetration of all 48 hotels around Asia and Australia under Swiss-Belhotel International management.
- Manage, and measure online brand exposure of Swiss-Belhotel International resulting in increased website traffic
  and direct revenue.
- Reach company's highest ever online acquisition ROI, 1:9 for all hotels, and over 1:39 for one hotel Increase company's affiliate marketing revenue by 20% within 3 months.
- · Build company's digital marketing blueprint Build new hotel's digital marketing setup guidance.
- Seal several long term corporate partnership for direct online booking promotion.
- Dominate search engine with proper SEO strategy, resulting organic search acquisition over 60% (higher than industry average).
- · Initiate company's mobile booking campaign and content marketing.
- · Rebuild and redesign company's website, and manage email marketing campaign.
- Company's new website bounce rate dropped from over 60% to just 15%.
- Create company's first ever mobile website.
- · Integrate company's new website with booking engine system.

## **E-COMMERCE CREATIVE LEADER**

2012-2013

Swiss-Belhotel International Hotels & Resorts

- Manage and control creative content production to boost company's online exposure and revenue.
- Shorten creative production time from 7 days to 3 days.
- · Build company creative blueprint.
- Integrate production system between marketing and creative department.
- · Rebuild and rebrand company's website and identity, and also manage company's daily email direct marketing.
- New company's website cause 20% increase in revenue.
- · Create company's digital asset management guidance.

## **E-COMMERCE AND DIGITAL CONSULTANT**

2008-2015

## Past partnership with:

- Ministry Trade of Indonesia
- ASEAN Foundation
- · Global Alliance for Improved Nutrition (GAIN), Switzerland
- 8 Etos
- iBuild
- · Bangun Mandiri Manageement
- Ellora Hotel and Resort Bali
- Several Indonesian small and medium-sized enterprises

## **EDUCATION**

# Universitas Padjadjaran, Majoring International Relations

Bandung, Indonesia

Final thesis: Quantitative Research on The Effectiveness of US Embassy Public Diplomacy on Facebook